Guide to the John Chipman Farrar Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1919-1967, undated; Series II; 1.46; (4 boxes)
  - Speeches and Talks
    - "My Friends, The Authors," Milwaukee, undated (Box 35)
    - New Haven, 1954 (Box 35)
    - New York University, 1958 (Box 35)
    - "Our Origin of the Species," an address at the New York Times National Book Fair, 1936 November 9 (Box 35)
    - Randolph-Macon Woman's College, 1949 (Box 35)
    - Scarborough School Talk, 1945 February 21 (Box 35)
    - "Town Hall, 3rd Lecture", undated (Box 35)
    - Miscellaneous notes and quotes for speeches, undated; 5 (Box 35)
  - "Tamburlaine the Great," by Christopher Marlowe, typescript, 1919 (Box 36)
    "Acting version, prepared under the direction of Edgar Montillion Woolley and Stephen Vincent Benét"
  - "U.S.A. and Victory," typescript, undated (Box 36)
  - "We Will Have Fun," by Edmund Black and John Knox, undated (Box 36)
  - Miscellaneous articles, undated; 5 (Box 36)
- Family Papers, 1934-1964; Series III; 1.04; (3 boxes)
  The series is organized into four subseries: Correspondence and Subject Files, Other Papers, Photographs, and Artwork and Objects. The Correspondence and Subject Files subseries is arranged alphabetically.
  The series reflects Farrar's personal life, such as his relationship with family members, as well as friendships with writers and artists. Among personal items included in the series are photographs of the Farrars and their friends. The Farrars were given artwork by Lynd Ward and Robert Chelsey Osborn. The series also contains part of a scrapbook created by Farrar and Hamilton Hadley to document their experience during WWI.
  - Correspondence and Subject Files
    - Farrar, Janice. Correspondence and personal papers, 1944-1952; 2 (Box 37)
    - Farrar, John Curtis. Correspondence, personal papers, and writings, 1941-1964; 9 (Box 37–38)
    - Farrar, Margaret. Correspondence, 1944-1952; 3 (Box 38)
    - Farrar, Sally Wright. Correspondence, 1941-1947; 2 (Box 38)
    - Correspondence on the passing of Sally Wright Farrar, 1948; 2 (Box 39)
  - Other Papers
    - Material removed from scrapbook "Yale 1919 and the War" compiled by Farrar and Hamilton Hadley, 1917-1919; 2 (Box 39)
  - Photographs
    - Doran, George H., circa 1926
      Includes etchings of Doran.
    - Farrar, John Chipman, 1934, undated (Box 39)
    - Farrar, Margaret, 1954-1960, undated (Box 39)
    - Hayward, Du Bose, undated
      Photograph by Doris Ulmann.
    - Lewis, Wilmarth, circa 1917 (Box 39)
    - Wylie, Ted, undated (Box 39)
  - Artwork and Objects
    - Woodcut of male nude by Lynd Ward, 1932 (Box 39)
      Paper; 6.75 X 4. 75 inches
    - Drawings by Robert Chelsey Osborn, undated (Box 39)
      Various drawings, paintings, and sketches; includes drawing of Elinor Wylie and of John Farrar with inscription "John, forward!"
    - Painting of a boat by P.C.W., undated
      Watercolour and gouache on paper; 12.25 X 9.5 inches
    - Cigar box and cigar belonging to Amy Lowell and given to Farrar following her death, circa 1925 (Box 40)
- Printed Material, 1916-1964; Series IV; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  The series contains printed materials either by or about John Chipman Farrar, dating from 1916 to 1974. The series includes certificates and honors presented to Farrar, clippings, pamphlets, programs and other serial publications.
  - Pamphlets and serials with contributions by Farrar, 1916-1964; 7 (Box 40–41)
  - Certificates and honors, 1946-1974 (Box 41)
  - Clippings, 1940-1951 (Box 41)
  - Pamphlets and programs, 1929-1964; 2 (Box 41)
- Oversize, 0.5; (1 box)
  - Photographs. Doran, George H., circa 1926 (Box 42)
  - Photographs. Hayward, Du Bose, undated (Box 42)
  - Artwork. Painting of a boat by P.C.W., undated (Box 42)